SR. DIRECTOR OF CLOUD / SAAS OPERATIONS Summary

Visionary committed to excellence with demonstrated experience in driving an entire organization into the future by innovating with state of the art technologies to solve problems with scale, stability and visibility. Championing the mentality of "whatever it takes" and showing others by leading by example, Â throughout my career I have provided a model and a definitive blueprint on the milestones required to move a company from good to GREAT!

Skills

- Operations
- DevOps Development
- Business Planning
- Team Building / Recruiting
- · Agile Methodology
- Optimization
- Data Driven Analysis
- Strategic Leadership
- Operational Management
- Systems Technology
- Database Technology
- Software Engineering
- Execution Plans

Experience

Sr. Director of Cloud / SaaS Operations May 2015 to Current Katmai il/4 Mableton, GA

- Network Operations and Application Delivery Responsible for operational delivery and Production support focusing on proactive monitoring, rapid response for SaaS and Application services.
- Develop and document resourcing roadmaps, budgets and schedules.
- Ensure team is properly engaged, aware of career milestones/path, aware of their role on the team and how it relates to others, lastly aware of their contributions to our overall goals.
- Lead all recruiting activities across the team.
- Collaborate with other Engineering teams to provide expertise and support on key initiatives with a focus on system availability and reliability
 (and ensuring a low MTTR).
- Identify gaps/risks early and establish mitigation plans (both technically & with regards to resources).
- Increase the overall visibility of their team, celebrate/track accomplishments and build relationships with key leaders in other groups.
- Continually strive for improvements in process, talent acquisition/retention, application time-to-market and quality.
- Create and review documentation and process regarding recurring issues, new standard operating procedures, knowledge transfer material.
- Led multidiscipline teams of over 25 people across multiple time zones.
- Built Global Operations Team including NOC and DevOps from the ground up.
- Transitioned company from On Premise Deployment Model to Managed Service Provider.
- Decreased Software Deployment times by 75% by implementing automated deployment / continuous deployment software.
- Instituted Technical Operations best practices and acceptance criteria in the Software Deployment process.
- Developed Executive / Operational / Client Facing Dashboards.
- Increased On Call Coverage in Foreign Geos and facilitated the use of the "Follow-the-Sun" methodology.
- Operations group leader in obtaining ISO / SSAE16 / FedRAMP attestations / certifications.
- Restructured Organization to align with business needs that separated Application Delivery team into 3 Separate teams "Build and Deploy", "Eyes on Glass" and "Infrastructure".
- Instrumental in winning client deals that doubled overall revenue from \$30M to \$60M in 1 years' time.
- Maintained Operational budget of over \$3 Million Dollars.
- Spear headed initiative to bring Software License compliance to 100%.
- Migrated entire company to Office 365 350 Users.
- Created Policies and Criteria to reign in Corporate IT Compliance/Governance.
- Instituted "white glove" service to reshape Corp IT perception.
- Created Corporate IT Infrastructure and Supplies Procurement program.
- Migrated company from Windows 7 to Windows 10 350 Users.
- Created Single Laptop Platform, reducing IT Overhead costs by 25%.
- Instituted Single Sign on Solution from Okta.
- Restructured Operational Procedures to align with new Agile Development Lifecycle methodology.
- Technologies: MongoDB, Red Hat Ceph, Apache Storm, Apache Karaf, Kafka, Elasticsearch, Logstash, Puppet, Linux (Ubuntu, RHEL), JIRA, Confluence.

Program Director, Enterprise Operations Apr 2015 to May 2015 IBM

- IBM Dallas, TX, April-2015 (Promotion).
- Operational Portfolio Extended to include 2 Major SaaS Enterprise Applications.

Senior Manager, SaaS Operations and App Delivery Mar 2012 to Apr 2015 IBM i½ City , STATE

- Increased compliance of Service Level Agreements by 47% for Top 50 clients during Peak Season safeguarding \$35M in annual client revenue
- Decreased Software Deployment times by 75% by implementing automated deployment / continuous deployment software.
- Decreased storage costs by 60% / increased performance by 25% by instituting / enforcing stricter data retention policies and audits-saving \$2.7 Million Annually.
- Created over 50 Different Executive / Operational Dashboards eliminating 30% of email traffic.
- Decreased Data Centers costs 20% by implementing wide scale consolidation efforts.
- Increased On call Coverage in Foreign Geos 20% to lighten On call load and facilitated the use of the "Follow-the-Sun" methodology.
- Decreased Operational head count by 15% by increasing levels of Automated Recovery / Monitoring.
- Spear headed initiative to bring Software License compliance to 100%.
- Restructured Operational Procedures to align with new Agile Development Lifecycle methodology.
- Successfully mentored and groomed three Level 3 leaders as a part of long term Succession Planning.
- Developed separate divisions to focus on "Day to Day" vs "Innovating for the Future".
- Navigated the turbulent political waters of an acquisition.
- Instrumental in Chaperoning IBM into the new era of SaaS / Cloud Manager Global SaaS Operations Digital Analytics IBM Dallas, TX, Nov-2012 (Promotion).
- Management role Extended to take over Global SaaS Operations Team in addition to the Oracle DB Team
- Manager Service Delivery / Databases Coremetrics, an IBM Company IBM Dallas, TX, March-2012 (Promotion).
- Took over Management of Oracle Database Operations Group.
- Restructured DB team to balance out On Call shifts and workload.
- Increased Operational Performance by 200%.
- Lead Database Platform move from Solaris to Centos to decrease license cost by 45%.
- Migrated 89 Production Databases from Oracle 10g to 11g.
- Reduced Storage footprint from 980TBs to 256TBs through auditing and clean up routines.

Operations Engineer Jan 2006 to Jan 2012

IBM i¹/₄ City, STATE

- Created/Adapted strong and stable change management processes.
- Participated / Lead rapid incremental Software Deployments.
- Developed Operational Best Practices.
- Day-to-day monitoring of client deliverables to ensure adherence to SLAs.
- Identifying and solving problems affecting data processing reliability and timeliness.
- Working with our SaaS Development organization to evolve product stability, efficiency, and manageability.
- Creating and configuring new data tenants for clients, as well as implementing new features.
- Managing performance, storage, and backups in a distributed system architecture.
- Developing tools and utilities in support of the Operations organization.
- Developed online applications to streamline operations for a medium sized corporation with multiple divisions.
- Analyzed, designed and developed software processes.
- Evaluated, installed, maintained, tested, and modified system software and supporting sub-systems; resolved complex installation procedures.
- Advised clients regarding the efficient operation and use of computerized client information systems and resources.
- Technologies: JBoss, Hadoop, MongoDB, Java, Teradata Aster, Tibco, IBM MQ Series, Linux (Ubuntu, Centos, Solaris, AIX), Perl, Bash, Korn Shell.

Education and Training

Masters , Information Systems 2011 University of Texas Arlington, Arlington Texas Information Systems Master of Science , Information Technology University of Texas at Arlington Business Administration

MBA 2010 University of Texas Arlington i¹/₄ City, State

BS , Computer Science 2005 University of North Texas $i^1\!\!/_{\!\!4}$ City , State Computer Science Skills

Streamline, Agile, AIX, Apache, auditing, balance, Bash, blueprint, budgets, Business Planning, Change Management, Client Relationship Management, Big Data, Data processing, Databases, Delivery, Documentation, IBM MQ Series, Information systems, ISO 27001/27002, Java, JBoss, Korn Shell, Team Building, Leadership, Linux, Director, Managing, Windows, MongoDB, Optimization, Oracle Database, Perl, Policies, Processes, Procurement, Quality, Recruiting, Red Hat, Service Level Agreements, Software Engineering, Solaris, Strategic, System architecture, Teradata, Tibco